本字幕由Yukun制作
主演：詹姆斯.斯图尔特
片名：后窗
联合主演：格蕾丝.凯丽
导演：阿尔弗雷德.希区柯克
[喵…]
Men, are you over 40?
[电台播音员]：朋友，你是否年过40？
When you wake up in the morning,do you feel tired and rundown?
早上起床时，是否感到疲惫？
Do you have that listless feeling?
是否无精打彩…
[这是L.B.杰弗利骨折的腿]
[摔碎的相机]
[电动剃须刀的声音]
[电话铃声]
- Jefferies. - Congratulations, Jeff.
- 我是杰弗利 - 恭喜你，杰夫
- For what? - Getting rid of that cast.
- 为什么？- 摆脱石膏呀
Who said I was getting rid of it?
谁说我摆脱了？
This is Wednesday.
今天是星期三
Seven weeks from the dayabcyou broke your leg. Yes or no?
七周前的今天，你摔断了腿，不是吗？
Gunnison, how did you get to be such a big editor with such a small memory?
乔那森，你这么没记性怎么当上编辑的？
Thrift, industry and hard work...
节俭、勤奋、努力工作
and catching the publisherabcwith his secretary.
还有抓住出版商的小辨子
- Did I get the wrong day? - No.
- 我记错日子了吗？- 没有
No, wrong week.
不，是记错了星期
Next Wednesday I emergeabcfrom this... plaster cocoon.
我下周三才拆石膏
That's too bad, Jeff. I can't be lucky every day.
那太糟了，杰夫，呃，我猜我不可能每天都走运的
Forget I called.
就当我没打电话吧
Yeah, I sure feel sorry for you, Gunnison.
我真替你难过，乔那森
Must be rough on you thinking of me wearing this cast another whole week.
我还要戴一整周的石膏，一定让你很难受
That one week is gonna cost me my best photographer,
是呀，我最好的摄影师没法工作
and you a big assignment.
你会错过一次极佳的任务
Where?
去哪儿？
- There's no point in even talking about it.
- 现在说这个没用了
- No, come on, where?
- 别这样，去哪？
Kashmir. Got a code tip from the bureau chief this morning.
克什米尔，今天早上从中情局得来的消息
The place is about to go up in smoke.
那地方要开战了
What did I tell you? Didn't I tell you that's the next place to watch?
我早说过要盯着那儿
- You did. Okay, when do I leave? Half hour, hour?
- 的确. 好吧，我什么时候动身？半个小时，一个小时后？
- With that cast on? You don't. - Stop sounding stuffy.
- 戴着石膏？别做梦了 - 别死板了
I can take pictures from a jeep or a water buffalo.
我可以在吉普车或水牛背上拍照
You're too valuable to the magazine for us to play around with.
你对我们杂志太重要了
I'll send Morgan or Lambert.Morgan or Lambert.
我会派摩根或兰博特去的
That's fine.
摩根和兰博特,好吧
I get myself half-killed for you, and you reward me by stealing my assignments.
我为你差点死掉，你却这样报答我
I didn't ask you to stand in the middle of that automobile race track.
我又没让你站在赛道中间
You asked for something dramatically different.
可你要求图片引人注目
- You got it. - So did you.
- 你得到了. - 是的
- Good-bye, Jeff. - Now, wait a minute, Gunnison.
- 再见,杰夫 - 不，等一下，乔那森
You've got to get me out of here.
让我去吧
Six weeks sitting in a two-room apartment...
六周时间，坐在这小公寓里
with nothing to do but look out the window at the neighbors.
什么也干不了，只能看着窗外的邻居
- Bye, Jeff. - No, Gunnison, I...
- 再见，杰夫 - 不，乔那森，我…
If you don't pull me out of this swamp of boredom,
如果你不把我从这无聊的沼泽中救出来，
- I'm gonna do something drastic.abc - Like what?
- 我会做出疯狂的事来的  - 例如？
"Like what?"  I'm gonna get married.
"例如？" 例如，我会结婚
- Then I'll never be able to go anywhere. - It's about time you got married.
- 然后我就可以去任务地方了 - 你是该结婚了
Before you turn into a lonesome and bitter old man.
趁你还没变成孤寡老人之前
Yeah, can't you just see me?
是啊，瞧瞧我
I'm rushing home to a hot apartment...
在闷热的家里...
to listen to the automatic laundry and the electric dishwasher...
听着自动洗衣机，洗碗机...
and the garbage disposal and the nagging wife.
和倒垃圾的声音，还有那些唠叨的妻子
Jeff, wives don't nag anymore, they discuss.
杰夫，现在的妻子不再唠叨了，她们只是在讨论
Is that so? Is that so?
是吗，是吗？
Maybe in the high-rent district they discuss.
在高档住宅区的可能是吧
In my neighborhood, they still nag.
在我这儿，她们还在唠叨
Yeah? Well, you know best. Call you later, Jeff.
是吗？可能是吧，回头再联系，杰夫
Yeah, have some good news the next time, huh?
下次带点好消息来，行吗？
Good morning.
早安
I said, "Good morning!"
我说：早安
Oh, good morning.
噢，早安
I wouldn't dig so deep if I were you.
瞧，换了我，就不会挖那么深
You're giving them far too much water.
你浇的水太多了
Why don't you shut up?
你为什么不闭嘴？
Well!
好吧
I do declare.
我敢肯定…
New York state sentence for a Peeping Tom...
纽约州判偷窥者汤姆入狱六个月
is six months in the workhouse.
Oh, hello, Stella.
你好，斯泰拉
They got no windows in the workhouse.
在监狱里没有窗户
In the old days, they used to put your eyes out with a red-hot poker.
你知道，要在以前，他们会用烧红的烙铁把你的眼珠挖出来
Any of those bikini bombshells you're always watching worth a red-hot poker?
为了偷窥比基尼而挨烙铁，值得吗？
Oh, dear. We've become a race of Peeping Toms.
天啊，我们快变成一群偷窥狂了
What people ought to do is get outside their own house and look in for a change.
“人们应该离开自己的屋子，去外面的世界寻找新的生活”
Yes, sir. How's that for a bit of homespun philosophy?
瞧，这朴素的人生观怎么样？
Reader's Digest, April 1939.
出自读者文摘，1939年4月刊
Well, I only quote from the best. Yeah.
对，我只引用最精彩的
You don't have to take my temperature this morning.
今天不用量体温了
Quiet. See if you can break 100.
安静，看你能否达到100度
I should have been a gypsy fortune-teller...
你知道，我本该是个吉普赛预言家...
instead of an insurance company nurse.
而不是保险公司的护士
I got a nose for trouble. Can smell it ten miles away.
我有个能预知灾祸的鼻子
可以闻到10英里外的麻烦
You heard of that market crash in 29?
你听说29日股票崩盘了吗？
I predicted that.
我预测到了
Just how did you do that, Stella?
你怎么做的，斯泰拉？
Oh, simple. I was nursing a director of General Motors.
简单，我当时在护理通用电气公司的老板
"Kidney ailment," they said. "Nerves," I said.
他们说他得了肾病，要我说是神经病
Then I asked myself, "What's General Motors got to be nervous about?"
于是我问自己，他为什么要紧张？
"Overproduction," I says. Collapse.
生产过剩，我猜，担心破产
When General Motors has to go to the bathroom ten times a day,
如果通用电器的老板每天上十次洗手间
the whole country's ready to let go.
其它的公司就更不用提了
Stella, in economics, a kidney ailment has no relationship to the stock market.
斯泰拉，从经济学的角度来看，肾病和股票是扯不上关系的
None whatsoever. It crashed, didn't it?
风马牛不相及
但股票是跌了
Yeah. I can smell trouble right here in this apartment.
我在你这公寓里就闻到了麻烦
First you smash your leg,
先是你摔断了腿
then you get to looking out the window, see things you shouldn't see.
然后又从窗口看你不该看的东西
Trouble.
麻烦
I can see you in court now surrounded by a bunch of lawyers in double-breasted suits.
我可以想像你在法庭上，被一群律师包围着
You're pleading. You say, "Judge, it was only a bit of innocent fun.
你辩护说：“法官大人，那不过是一点毫无恶意的消遣”
I love my neighbors, like a father."
我喜欢我的邻居，像父亲那样喜欢他们
And the judge says, "Well, congratulations.
法官说：“好吧，祝贺你”
You've just given birth to three years in Dannemora."
“你只需在丹诺玛坐三年牢”
Right now, I'd welcome trouble.
现在，我就喜欢麻烦
You've got a hormone deficiency.
你荷尔蒙分泌不足
How can you tell from a thermometer?
只看体温表，你怎么知道？
Those bathing beauties you've been watching haven't raised your temperature one degree.
那些洗澡的美女一个月也没能让你的体温升高一度
Here we go.
来吧
One more week.
还有一周
I think you're right.
我想你是对的
- I think there is gonna be trouble around here. - I knew it.
- 我想这儿是有点麻烦 - 我就知道
Ooh. Do you ever heat that stuff?
噢，你不能把它先热一下吗？
- Gives your circulation something to fight. - Oh, I see.
-这是为了刺激你的血液循环 -我明白了
- What kind of trouble? - Lisa Fremont.
-什么麻烦？ -丽莎.弗里蒙特
You kidding? She's a beautiful young girl,
开玩笑，她是个美女
and you're a reasonably healthy young man.
而你又是个很健康的男人
- She expects me to marry her. - That's normal.
他希望我娶她. - 这很正常
- I don't want to. - That's abnormal.
- 可我不想 - 那可不正常.
I'm just not ready for marriage.
我只是还没准备好结婚
Every man's ready for marriage when the right girl comes along.
每个男人都准备好了，只要有合适的女孩
Lisa Fremont is the right girl for any man with half a brain...
丽莎是每个男人都梦寐以求的
- who can get one eye open. - She's all right.
- 她是不错
- What did you do, have a fight? - No.
- 你们吵架了？ - 没有
- Her father loading up the shotgun? - What?
- 她父亲想拿枪打你？ - 什么？
- Please, Stella. - It's happened before, you know.
- 别这样，斯泰拉 - 这种事常发生，你知道
Some of the world's happiest marriages have...
天底下最美满的婚姻
started "under the gun," as you might say.
往往开始于“严密监视之下”
No, she's just not the girl for me.
她不适合我
Yeah, she's only perfect.
她只是很完美
She's too perfect. She's too talented.
她太完美，太优秀
She's too beautiful. She's too sophisticated.
太美丽，太成熟，
She's too everything, but what I want.
总之太好了，却不是我要的
Is what you want something you can discuss?
她哪里不好，说说看？
What? It's very simple, Stella.
什么？很简单，斯泰拉
She belongs to that rarefied atmosphere of Park Avenue:
她属于公园大街那种高雅的氛围
expensive restaurants and literary cocktail parties.
住高档酒店，出席有品味的鸡尾酒会
People with sense belong wherever they're put.
有头脑的人可以适应任何环境
Can you imagine her tramping around the world with a camera bum...
你能想像她跟一个带着相机
who never has more than a week's salary in the bank?
没有积蓄的男人浪迹天涯吗？
If she was only ordinary.
她要是普通一点多好！
You never gonna get married?
你永远不打算结婚？
I'll probably get married one of these days,
没准过几天我就会结婚
but when I do, it's gonna be to someone who thinks of life...
如果我结婚，绝不能找一个
not just as a new dress and a lobster dinner...
只知道买新衣服，吃龙虾大餐...
and the latest scandal.
爱打听是非的女人
I need a woman who's willing to... Hold it.
我需要一个愿意…扶着点
Who's willing to go anywhere and do anything and love it.
愿意跟我去任何地方，做任何事的女人
So the honest thing for me to do is just call the whole thing off.
所以我最好还是放弃对她的幻想
Let her find somebody else.
让她找别人好了
Yeah, I can hear you now.
我明白了
"Get out of my life, you perfectly wonderful woman. You're too good for me."
“离开我吧，完美的女神，我配不上你”
Look, Mr. Jefferies, I'm not an educated woman, but I can tell you one thing:
我没读过什么书，但我可以告诉你
When a man and a woman see each other and like each other,
如果两个人一见钟情
they ought to come together, wham,
他们就该砰地一声撞在一起，
like a couple of taxis on Broadway...
就像路上的两辆的士
and not sit around analyzing each other...
而不是坐着，像标本一样，彼此分析
like two specimens in a bottle.
There's an intelligent way to approach marriage.
对婚姻来说，这可不理智
Intelligence.
理智？
Nothing has caused the human race so much trouble as intelligence.
没有比“理智”更容易招惹麻烦的了
Modern marriage.
所谓的现代婚姻
We've progressed emotionally. Baloney.
我们在情感上更成熟了
Once it was see somebody, get excited, get married.
胡扯
以前的人只要见个面，觉得心动，就结婚
Now, it's read a lot of books,
现在呢，读一大堆书，
fence with a lot of four-syllable words, psychoanalyze each other...
用复杂的术语相互分析
until you can't tell the difference...
直到你们不能区分彼此
between a petting party and a civil service exam.
搞得亲热聚会像公务员考试一样
People have different emotional levels...
人们的情商各不相同
When I married Myles, we were both a couple of maladjusted misfits.
我和迈尔斯结婚时，就有性格差异
We are still maladjusted, and we have loved every minute of it.
现在还是这样，但我们珍惜在一起的每一刻
That's fine, Stella. Now, would you fix me a sandwich, please?
真好，斯泰拉，你能帮我做个三明治吗？
Yes, I will. And I'll spread a little common sense on the bread.
好的，我要在面包上面涂点“常识”
Lisa's loaded to her fingertips with love for you.
丽莎非常爱你
I got two words of advice for you: Marry her.
听我一句，娶她吧
- She pay you much? - Oh.
- 她付你多少钱？ - 噢
There you are.
好了
- Here's the key. - Thank you.
- 这是钥匙 - 多谢
If you want anything, just ring.
有什么需要就按铃
Come on over here. Come on.
过来，来吧
Window shopper.
偷窥高手
How's your leg?
-腿怎样了？
It hurts a little.
还有点痛
- And your stomach? - Empty as a football.
- 肚子呢？ -空得像个足球
And your love life?
你的爱情生活呢？
Not too active.
一般
Anything else bothering you?
有什么困扰吗？
Mm-hmm.
Who are you?
你是谁？
Reading from top to bottom:
看仔细了，
Lisa...
丽莎
Carol...
卡洛
Fremont.
弗里蒙特
Is this the Lisa Fremont who never wears the same dress twice?
这个就是从不把一条裙子穿两遍的丽莎？
Only because it's expected of her.
这是专门订做的
It's right off the Paris plane.
刚刚从法国用飞机运来
- Do you think it'll sell? - That depends on the quote.
-你觉得会畅销吗？ -那得看价格如何
Let's see now. There's the airplane ticket over and import duties, hidden taxes,
你看，得加上航空运费、关税、间接费用和利润
profit markup... A steal at $ 1,100.
1,100美元，很划算
Eleven hundred? They ought to list that dress on the stock exchange.
1,100？应该把它送到股票交易所去上市
We sell a dozen a day in this price range.
我们今天卖了12件，都是这个价
Who buys them, tax collectors?
谁买的？ 收税的？
Even if I had to pay, it would be worth it,
即使让我自己付钱，也值得
- just for the occasion. - Something big going on somewhere?
-只在重要场合穿 -有什么重要的晚会吗？
It's going on right here. It's a big night.
就在这儿，今晚
It's just an old run-of-the-mill Wednesday.
这只是一个普通的周三晚上
The calender's full of them.
日历上有的是
It's opening night of the last depressing week of L.B. Jefferies in a cast.
今晚是“L.B.杰弗利戴石膏的最后沮丧一周”公开首演
Well, I haven't noticed a big demand for tickets.
呃，我没看到有人买票
That's because I bought out the house.
那是因为今晚我包场了
You know, this cigarette box has seen better days.
这盒烟曾经风麾一时
I picked that up in Shanghai, which has also seen better days.
我在上海买的，那地方也曾风麾一时
It's cracked and you never use it.
都裂了，你从没用过它
It's too ornate.
它太奢华了
I'm sending up a plain, flat, silver one with your initials.
我送个普通的银烟盒给你，刻上你的名字
That's no way to spend your hard-earned money.
我可不想花你的辛苦钱
I wanted to.
我愿意
Ooh!
What would you think of starting off with dinner at 21?
你觉得共进一顿“21号”餐厅的美味晚餐如何？
You have, perhaps, an ambulance downstairs?
你把救护车叫来了？
No, better than that: 21.
不，比那更好，“21号”餐厅
Thank you for waiting, Carl. The kitchen's right there on the left.
多谢你了，卡尔，厨房在左边
I'll take the wine.
我来拿酒
- Good evening, Mr. Jefferies. - Carl.
-晚上好，杰弗利先生 -卡尔
- Just put everything in the oven on low. - Yes, madame.
-把东西放炉里子里就行了 -好的，女士
- Let's open the wine now. - All right.
-我们来开酒 -好吧
- It's a Montrachet. - A great big glassful.
-是蒙拉谢(酒名) -要用大杯子
There's a corkscrew right over there.
那儿有开瓶器，
Here, I'll do it.
让我来
- Big enough? - Yeah, fine.
-够大吗？ -够了
I can't think of anything more boring or tiresome than what you've been through.
我想不出比被困在家里更泛味，无聊的事了
- and the last week must be the hardest. - Let me, sir.
-上周肯定是最难熬的 -让我来吧，先生
All right. Yeah, I want to get this thing off and get moving.
好吧，是呀，我真想把这东西弄掉，好好活动活动
I'm going to make this a week you'll never forget.
我要把这周变成最你难忘的一周
Fine, thanks.
好的，谢谢
Just a minute, Carl.
等一下，卡尔
- This will take care of the taxi as well. - Thank you, Miss Fremont.
打的士的钱也在里面了
- Have a pleasant dinner, Mr. Jefferies. - All right. Good night.
-谢谢你，弗里蒙特小姐，祝您用餐愉快，杰弗利先生 -好的，晚安
Good night.
晚安
What a day I've had.
今天可真忙呀
- Are you tired? - Not a bit.
- 你累了 - 点也不
I was all morning in a meeting,
整个上午都在和CEO开会，
then I had to dash to the Waldorf for a quick drink with Madame Dufrene...
然后赶去见杜弗兰太太
who's just over from Paris with some spy reports.
她刚从巴黎带回一些商业信息
I had to go to 21 and have lunch with the Harper's Bazaar people.
然后又去“21号”餐厅和代理商吃午餐
That's when I ordered dinner.
于是我在那儿订了晚餐
Then I had two fall showings 20 blocks apart.
然后又连开了两场秋季服装展示会
Then I had to have a cocktail with Leland and Slim Hayward.
又与利兰和海沃德一起喝鸡尾酒，
We're trying to get his new show.
我们准备为他开一个新的发布会
Then I had to dash back and change.
接着赶回来换衣服
Now, tell me, what was Mrs. Hayward wearing?
告诉我，海沃德太太穿的什么
- She looked wonderfully cool. - She did?
她看上去太漂亮了，
She had on the most divine Italian hand-printed...
她穿着上等的意大利手工印制的…
Oh, Italian?
噢，意大利的？ [嘲讽的语气]
Oh, you. Italian. Imagine.
-是意大利的，想想看 -噢，你…
To think I planted three nice items...
我今天在报纸上用了三个专题来介绍你
- ...in the columns about you today. - You did?
- 真的？
- You can't buy that kind of publicity. - I know.
- 知名度是钱买不到的 - 我知道
Someday you may want to open up a studio of your own here.
有一天，你也许想在这里开个自己的工作室
How would I run it from, say, Pakistan?
我怎么顾得过来？如果我在，比如说，巴基斯坦
Jeff...
杰夫，
isn't it time you came home?
别再四处奔波了
You could pick your assignment.
你可以自己挑选工作
- I wish there was one I wanted. - Make the one you want.
-希望有我喜欢的 -那就创造一个
- You mean leave the magazine? - Yes.
- 你是说离开杂志社？ - 对
- For what? - For yourself and me.
- 为什么？ - 为了你和我
I could get you a dozen assignments tomorrow:
我可以提供一打工作让你挑选
fashions, portraits.
时尚杂志、人物摄影
- Now, don't laugh. I could do it. - That's what I'm afraid of.
- 别笑，我是认真的 - 那才是我害怕的
Can you see me driving down to the fashion salon in a jeep...
你能想像我开着吉普车，装着军靴
wearing combat boots and a three-day beard?
胡子邋遢地去参加时尚沙龙吗？
Wouldn't that make a hit?
能行吗？
I could see you looking very handsome and successful...
我能想像，你会是个英俊的...
in a dark blue flannel suit.
身着法兰绒西装的成功人士
Let's stop talking nonsense, shall we? Hmm?
我们别说废话了，好吗？
Guess I'd better start setting up for dinner.
我还是去准备晚饭吧
To see you
Is to love you
And I see you
Everywhere
In the sunrise
In the moonglow
Anyplace I look
You're there
To see you
Is to want you
And I see you all the time
On a sidewalk
In a doorway
On the lonely stairs I climb
Someday
Let me show you
How happy endings start
You'll find how well I know you
Because to know you at all
Is to know you by heart
To see you is to love you
And you're never out of sight
And I love you
And I'll see you
In the same old dream
Tonight
Miss Lonelyhearts.
可怜的单身女士
At least that's something you'll never have to worry about.
至少你从不用为此忧虑
Oh? You can see my apartment from here, all the way up on 63rd Street?
你怎么知道？你能从这儿看到我在63街的公寓？
No, not exactly, but we have a little apartment here...
不，不能。不过这儿有间小公寓
that's probably as popular as yours.
也许和你的公寓一样热闹
You remember, of course, Miss Torso, the ballet dancer?
你还记得多索小姐，那个芭蕾舞演员吗？
She's like a queen bee with her pick of the drones.
她像个蜂王一样挑选雄蜂
I'd say she's doing a woman's hardest job: juggling wolves.
她正在做一件危险的事：招蜂引蝶
Thank you.
多谢
She picked the most prosperous-looking one.
她选了个最富有的家伙
She's not in love with him... or any of them.
她不爱他，也不爱其它两个
How can you tell that from here?
你怎知道的
You said it resembled my apartment, didn't you?
你说它与我的公寓一样，不是吗？
I hope they're cooked this time.
但愿这次煮熟了
[左边调钟的人是导演希区柯克，他喜欢 在自己的电影里露一脸，相当于个性签名]
Where's that wonderful music coming from?
这美妙的音乐从哪来的？
Some songwriter over there in the studio apartment.
是对面的那个作曲家
Well... He lives alone.
他一个人住
Probably had a very unhappy marriage.
可能经历过一次不幸的婚姻
Oh, it's enchanting.
噢，太动听了
It's almost as if it were being written especially for us.
就像是特地为我们而作的
Hmm. No wonder he's having so much trouble with it.
难怪他写得这么费劲
At least you can't say the dinner isn't right.
至少你得说晚餐还可以
Lisa... it's perfect.
丽莎，棒极了
As always.
向来如此
There can't be that much difference between people and the way they live.
人与人之间没有那么大的差别
- We all eat, talk, drink, laugh, wear clothes. - Well, now, look...
- 我们都吃饭、喝水、聊天、穿衣 - 你瞧
If you're saying all this because you don't want to tell me the truth,
如果你有难言之隐
because you're hiding something from me, then maybe I can understand.
想对我隐瞒，我可以理解
- I'm not hiding anything. It's just that... - It doesn't make sense.
- 我没有隐瞒什么 - 还说没有
What's so different about it here from there or anyplace you go...
你去过的地方与这儿有何不同
- ...that one person couldn't live in both places just as easily?
让你觉得别人无法适应
Some people can. If you'll let me explain...
有的人可以，如果你听我解释
What is it but traveling, taking pictures?
你的工作除了观光，不停拍照，还有什么？
It's like being a tourist on an endless vacation.
不过是不停地四处旅游罢了
Okay. That's your opinion. You're entitled to it. Now let me give you my side...
好吧，这是你的想法，现在听我说
It's ridiculous to say that it can only be done...
真可笑，我就不信除了你，其它人做不到
by a special,private little group of anointed people.
I made a simple statement, a true statement,
也许我没说清楚，但那是事实
but I can back it up if you'll just shut up for a minute.
我可以证明我的观点，只要你嘴
If your opinion is as rude as your manner,
如果你的意见和态度一样粗鲁
I don't think I care to hear it.
我将无法接受
Come on now. Simmer down. You...
别这样，冷静点
I can't fit in here. You can't fit in there.
“我适应不了这里，你适应不了那里”
According to you, people should be born, live and die...
-照你的说法，人们应该在一个地方生老病死
- ...on the same spot! - Shut up!
- 闭嘴
Did you ever eat fish heads and rice?
你吃过鱼头和大米吗？
Of course not.
没有
Well, you might have to if you went with me.
跟我在一起就得吃
Did you ever try to keep warm in a C-54 at 15,000 feet, 20 degrees below zero?
你坐过飞行高度15,000尺，零下20度的飞机吗？
I do it all the time,
经常是那样
whenever I have a few minutes after lunch. Did you ever get shot at?
你遭过枪击吗？
Did you ever get run over?
精疲力尽过吗？
Did you ever get sandbagged because somebody got unfavorable publicity from your camera?
因为你拍的照片令人不悦，而遭人暴打吗？
Did you ever... Those high heels... They'll be great in the jungle.
在丛林中穿高跟鞋真是个好主意
- And the nylons and those six-ounce lingerie. - Three!
- 还有尼龙裙子和六英寸的高跟鞋 - 三英寸
Three. They'll make a big hit in Finland, just before you freeze to death.
三英寸，在芬兰穿肯定很棒，如果你没被冻死的话
If there's one thing I know, it's how to wear the proper clothes.
我知道该穿什么衣服
Yeah, yeah. Try and find a raincoat in Brazil,
对，在巴西穿雨衣
even when it isn't raining.
即便没下雨
Lisa, in this job you carry one suitcase.
丽莎，这工作只能带一个衣箱
Your home is the available transportation.
没有旅馆住
You don't sleep very much. You bathe less.
睡眠和洗浴没法保证
And sometimes the food that you eat...
有时候，你吃的食物也是最恶心的动物做的
is made from things that you couldn't even look at when they're alive!
Jeff, you don't have to be deliberately repulsive just to impress me I'm wrong.
杰夫，你不用为了吓我，而故意说得这么可怕
"Deliberately repulsive?" I'm trying to make it sound good.
“故意说得可怕”？我已经是轻描淡写了
You just have to face it. You're not meant for that kind of a life.
你得承认，你适应不了这种生活
Few people are.
几乎没人做得到
You're too stubborn to argue with.
你真不可理喻
I'm not stubborn. I'm just truthful.
我没有，这是实话
I know. A lesser man would have told me it was one long holiday,
你本可以说这只是个漫长的假日
and I would have awakened to a rude disillusionment.
来鼓励我
Well, now, wait a minute.
等一下，等一下，
If you want to get vicious on this thing, I'd be happy to accommodate you.
如果你想克服这一切，我很愿意帮助你
No, I don't particularly want that.
不，算了吧
So that's it?
就这样？
You won't stay here, and I can't go with you.
你不愿留下来，我也不会跟你走
It would be the wrong thing.
那会是个错误
You don't think either one of us could ever change?
我们中的一个不能改变吗？
Right now it doesn't seem so.
暂时看来不会
I...I'm in love with you.
我爱你，
I don't care what you do for living.
我不在乎你以什么为生
I'd just like to be part of it somehow.
我只想成为你生活的一部分
It's deflating to find out...
真遗憾...
the only way I can be part of it is to take out a subscription to your magazine.
看来只能靠订阅你的杂志来了解你的工作了
I guess I'm not the girl I thought I was.
看来我没有想像中坚强
There's nothing wrong with you. You've got this town in the palm of your hand.
不是你的错，丽莎，你已经适应了这里的生活
Not quite, it seems.
不完全是
Good-bye, Jeff.
再见，杰夫
You mean good night.
你是说晚安
I mean what I said.
不，是再见
Well, Lisa...
丽莎
couldn't we just...
为什么我们不能…
Couldn't we just... keep things status quo?
为什么我们不能维持现状呢？
Without any future?
不考虑将来？
Well, when am I gonna see you again?
几时能再见你？
Not for a long time.
不会太久
At least... not until tomorrow night.
至少在明晚之前
[女人尖叫，摔杯子的声音]
Hey, rain.
下雨了
Wait, I'll get the clock. Oh, no.
等等，还有闹钟，噢，见鬼
Pull it...
拉一下
In you go.
快进去
噢…
[01:55]
[02:35]
You can't come in. It's much too late.
你不能进来，太晚了
No, not now.
不，现在不行
No, I said good night.
不，我说：“晚安”了
What's that supposed to be, ma'am?
那是什么？夫人
It's called "Hunger."
我叫它“饥饿”
You'd think the rain would have cooled things off.
你以为下雨后会降温？
- All it did was make the heat wet. - That's it, that's it.
- 只会变得更闷热 - 就是那儿
That's stiff right there. Right there.
就是那儿酸痛
The insurance company would be much happier...
保险公司会很高兴的
if you'd sleep in bed at night instead of in that wheelchair.
如果你每晚睡在床上，而不是在轮椅上
- How do you know? - Eyes are all bloodshot.
- 你怎么知道的？ - 你满眼都是血丝
- Must have been watching out that window for hours. - Yeah, I was.
- 一定是盯着窗外看了好几个钟头 - 的确
What are you gonna do if one of them catches you?
要是被人发现了怎么办？
It depends which one. Miss Torso, for example...
那得看是谁发现了，如果是多索小姐…
You keep your mind off her.
别乱想了
She sure is the "eat, drink and be merry" girl.
她肯定是个及时行乐的人
Yeah, she'll wind up fat, alcoholic and miserable.
对，酗酒、发胖，最后晚景凄凉
Yeah.
可能吧
Speaking of misery, poor Miss Lonelyhearts...
说到凄凉，可怜的单身小姐，
She drank herself to sleep again, alone.
她又一个人喝到睡着
Poor soul. Maybe one day she'll find her happiness.
可怜人，有一天她会找到幸福的
Yeah, and some man will lose his.
对，不知道谁这么倒霉
Isn't there anybody in the neighborhood who could cast an eye in her direction?
附近有人适合她吗？
I don't know.
不知道
It might be that the salesman will be available soon.
那个推销员可能会
Oh, him and his wife splitting up?
跟他妻子闹翻的那个？
I just can't figure it.
我不太明白
He went out several times last night in the rain,
昨晚下雨时他出去了好几次
carrying his sample case.
带着他的推销箱子
- He's a salesman, isn't he? - What would he be selling at 3:00 in the morning?
- 他是个推销员，不是吗？ - 早上三点出去推销什么？
Flashlights. Luminous dials for watches.
手电筒、夜光手表
House numbers that light up.
能发光的门牌号码
I don't think so. I don't think so.
我看不像
I think he was taking something out of the apartment.
我看他是在往外搬东西
Uh-huh. His personal effects.
那是他自己的事
He's gonna run out on her, the coward.
他想抛弃她，这个懦夫
Yeah. Sometimes it's worse to stay than it is to run.
走为上策
Yeah, well, it takes a particularly low type of man to do a thing like that.
没种的男人才那样
How about this morning?
今天早上怎么样？
- Any further developments? - No.
- 有什么进展吗？ - 没有
The shades are all drawn in the apartment.
他们的窗帘一直拉着
- In this heat? - Yeah.
- 这么热的天气？- 对
They're up now.
可是，现在打开了
- Get back, get back. - Where do you want me to go?
- 退后，退后 - 去哪儿？
- Get out of sight. Get out of sight. - What's the matter?
- 怎么啦？ - 别让他看见
The salesman's looking out of his window. You see?
那家伙在看窗外，你瞧
- Get back. He'll see you. - I'm not shy. I've been looked at before.
- 退后，他会看见你的 - 我又不害羞，我经常被人看
That's no ordinary look.
他的表情很怪
That's the kind of look a man gives when he's afraid somebody might be watching.
只有担心别人发现自己的秘密，才会有这种表情
Get away from there. Get away from there.
走开，走开，
He'll be after you. Go on, into the house.
他会来抓你的，进屋去，
Into the house. Shoo, shoo.
进屋去，唏，唏…
Good-bye, Mr. Jefferies. See you tomorrow.
再见，杰弗利先生，明天见
Uh-huh.
嗯哈
And don't sleep in that chair again.
别再睡在轮椅上了
Uh-huh.
嗯哈
"Uh-huh. Uh-huh." Great conversationalist.
嗯哈，嗯哈，就知道嗯哈
Stella...
斯泰拉
take those binoculars out and bring them here, will you?
把望远镜拿给我，好吗？
Trouble.
麻烦，
I can smell it.
我闻到了
I'll be glad when they crack that cast, and I can get outta here.
真希望你早点拆石膏，我就不用再来了
Uh-huh.
嗯哈
How far does a girl have to go before you'll notice her?
一个女孩要怎样做才能让你动心？
If she's pretty enough, she doesn't have to go anywhere.
只要她足够漂亮，什么也不用做
She just has to "be."
只要她够漂亮(但她必须存在) [英文双关语]
Well, ain't I? Pay attention to me.
我不够吗？注意一下我吧
I'm not exactly on the other side of the room.
这样还不够注意吗？
Your mind is... and when I want a man, I want all of him.
我还要你的心，我要你的全部
Don't you ever have any problems?
你从来没烦恼吗？
I have one now.
现在有一个
So do I.
我也是
Tell me about it.
说说看
Why...
为什么…
Why would a man leave his apartment three times...
为什么一个男人在雨夜提着箱子离开家三次
on a rainy night with a suitcase...
and come back three times?
然后又回来三次？
He likes the way his wife welcomes him home.
他喜欢看妻子欢迎他回家
No, no. No, no.
不，不…
No, no. Not this salesman's wife.
推销员的妻子可不会
And why didn't he go to work today?
为什么他今天不去工作？
Homework. It's more interesting.
做家务吧，很有趣的
What's interesting about a butcher knife...
那么杀猪刀呢？
and a small saw...
还有一把锯子
wrapped in newspaper?
用报纸包着，嗯？
Nothing, thank heaven.
但愿没什么
Why hasn't he been in his wife's bedroom all day?
为什么他一整天都不进妻子的房间？
I wouldn't dare answer that.
我不敢回答
Well, listen. I'll answer it, Lisa.
我来回答，
There's something terribly wrong.
一定发生了什么可怕的事
- And I'm afraid it's with me. - What do you think?
- 恐怕是发生在我身上了 [指杰夫心不在焉] - 你认为呢？
Something too frightful to utter.
我不想谈论恐怖的事
He went out a few minutes ago in his undershirt, hasn't come back.
他几分钟前穿着汗衫出去了，现在还没回来
That would be a terriblejob.
那可不是件容易处理的事
Just how would you start to cut up a human body?
如果要你分尸，你会从哪下手？
Jeff, I'll be honest with you. You're beginning to scare me.
杰夫，说实话，你开始吓着我了
Jeff, did you hear what I said?
杰夫，你听见了吗？
- You're beginning to scare... - Shh! Shh, he's coming back.
- 你开始吓着… -唏，唏，他回来了…
- Jeff, if you could only see yourself! - What's the matter?
- 杰夫，管好你自己吧 - 怎么啦？
Sitting around looking out of the window to kill time is one thing,
看窗外消磨时间是一回事
but doing it the way you are with binoculars...
但像你这样用望远镜偷窥
and wild opinions about every little thing you see is diseased!
而且满脑子胡思乱想是变态
Do you think I consider it recreation?
你以为我这是在消遣吗？
I don't know what you consider it,
我不管你叫它什么
but if you don't stop it, I'm getting out of here.
如果你不停止，我马上就走
- What's the... - What is it you're looking for?
- 为什么？ - 你到底在看什么？
I just want to find out what's the matter with the salesman's wife.
我只想知道推销员的妻子怎么了
Does that make me sound like a madman?
这有何不对？
- What makes you think there's something the matter with her? - A lot of things.
- 你怎么知道她出事了？ - 太不正常了
She's an invalid. She demands constant care.
她有病在身，需要人贴身照顾
Yet not the husband or anybody else has been in to see her all day. Why?
可一整天来，没人去过她的房间，为什么？
Maybe she died.
也许她病故了
Where's the doctor?
怎么没看见医生，
Where's the undertaker?
还有殡仪馆的人呢？
She could be sleeping, under sedatives.
她可能服了镇静剂，睡着了
He's in there now. There's nothing to see.
他回来了，没什么可看的
There is something. I've seen it through that window.
有，我都从窗户里看见了
I've seen bickering and family quarrels...
我看到他们争吵，
and mysterious trips at night...
丈夫午夜外出，
and knives and saws and rope.
还有刀、锯和绳子
Now, since last evening, not a sign of the wife. Tell me where she is.
而妻子却从此不见踪影，你说她在哪？
- I don't know. - What's she doing? Where is she?
- 我不知道 - 她在干嘛，她在哪？
Maybe he's leaving his wife. I don't know. I don't care!
也许他们分居了，我不知道，我不管
Lots of people have knives and saws and ropes around their houses.
很多人家里有刀、锯和绳子
And lots of men don't speak to their wives all day.
而且很多丈夫整天都不与妻子讲话
Lots of wives nag and men hate them and trouble starts,
很多妻子唠叨，丈夫心烦，所以吵架
but few of them end up in murder, if that's what you're thinking.
但没人会因此杀人，别胡思乱想了
It's pretty hard for you to keep away from that word, isn't it?
看，你也想到谋杀了，不是吗？
You could see all that he did, couldn't you?
你看到了他所做的一切，对吗？
- Of course, I... - You could see because the shades were up...
- 当然你看到了，我... - 因为窗帘是开着的
and he walked along the corridor and the street and the backyard.
而且你看到他在走廊、后院和街上的活动
- I've seen him... - Jeff, do you think a murderer would let you see all that?
杰夫，你觉得凶手会让你看到这些吗？
- That he wouldn't pull the shades and hide behind them? - He's being clever.
- 难道他不知道拉上窗帘，掩人耳目？ - 这正是他聪明的地方
- He's being nonchalant. - And that's where you're not being clever.
- 他装作若无其事… - 这正是你糊涂的地方
- A murderer would never parade his crime in front of an open window. - Why not?
- 凶手绝不会开窗炫耀犯罪过程 - 为何不可？
For all you know, there's something sinister going on.
照你的说法，那扇窗子里也有人在犯罪？
Where? Oh.
哪儿？噢
No comment.
我不知道
Let's start from the beginning again, Jeff.
从头再说一遍，杰夫
Tell me everything you saw...
告诉我你看到的一切
and what you think it means.
和你对整件事的看法
Yeah?
喂
The name on the second floor rear mailbox reads...
二楼邮箱的名字是
"Mr. and Mrs. Lars..."
拉兹先生和太太
That's L-a-r-s. "Lars Thorwald."
拉兹.索沃德
What's the number of the apartment?
门牌号码是多少？
125 W. Ninth Street.
西九大街125号
Thank you, dear.
谢谢，亲爱的
Okay, chief. What's my next assignment?
好的，长官，下一个任务是什么？
Just go home.
回家去
All right, but what's he doing now?
好的，现在他在干什么？
He's just sitting in the living room in the dark.
他坐这黑暗的客厅里
Hasn't gone near the bedroom.
还没靠近过卧室
Now you go home and get some sleep. Good night.
你回去休息吧，晚安
Good night.
晚安
- What's it all about, Jeff? - Look, Doyle, I can't tell you over the telephone.
- 什么事？杰夫 - 瞧，多尤，这事不能在电话里谈
- You have to be here and see the whole setup. - Important?
- 你得过来亲眼看看 - 很重要吗？
It's probably nothing important at all.
可能什么都不是
It's just a little neighborhood murder.
可能是个谋杀案
- Did you say, "murder?" - Yes, as a matter of fact, I did say murder.
- 你是说“谋杀”？- 是，我是说“谋杀”
- Come now. - My only thought was throwing a little business your way.
- 噢，别逗了 - 我只想帮你的忙
I figured a detective would jump at the chance of something to detect.
我想一个称职的侦探不会放过任何机会
- I'm not working. - What?
- 我下班了 - 什么？
This happens to be my day off.
我今天休息
- I usually took my best pictures on my day off. - I'll drop by.
- 我最好的照片都是休息时拍的 - 我会来的
Okay, Doyle. As soon as you can.
好的，多尤，快点
Bless your heart, Stella.
太谢谢你了，斯泰拉
Gee whiz, look at this.
啧，啧，瞧瞧
I can't tell you what a welcome sight this is.
这真是太棒了！
- No wonder your husband still loves you. - The police?
- 难怪你丈夫还爱你 - 警察？
What? You called the police?
什么？你打电话给警察了？
Not exactly. Not exactly.
不完全是.不完全是
Not an official call. It's an old friend of mine.
不算正式报警，他是我的朋友
An old, ornery friend of mine.
一个普通的老朋友
Just where do you suppose he cut her up?
你认为他会在哪儿分尸？
Of course. The bathtub.
当然，是在浴缸里
That's the only place where he could have washed away the blood.
只有在那，他才能洗去血迹
He better get that trunk out of there before it starts to leak.
他最好在血流出来之前，把那箱子弄走
Harry?
哈利？
Look, look, Mr. Jefferies.
瞧，瞧，杰弗利先生
I thought Doyle would be here...
早知道多尤赶不过来
by the time the trunk left, or I'd have called the police.
我该报警的，现在全完了
- Now we're gonna lose it. - Hold everything.
- 别急 - 别干傻事
Don't do anything foolish. I'm just gonna get the name off that freight truck.
我去看看搬运车的车牌
I'll keep an eye on the alley.
我会盯着小巷
Long distance.
长途电话
You didn't see the killing or the body.
你没看到杀人或尸体
How do you know there was a murder?
怎么知道是谋杀？
Everything this fellow's done has been suspicious:
因为他行迹可疑
trips at night in the rain, knives and saws and trunks with rope,
雨夜外出，还有刀、锯和用绳子捆绑的箱子
and now this wife that isn't there anymore.
而现在妻子又不见了
I admit it all has a mysterious sound.
我得承认是有点可疑
It could be any number of things. Murder's the least possible.
但有许多可能性，不一定是谋杀
Doyle, don't tell me he's an unemployed magician,
噢，多尤，别告诉我他是个失业的魔术师
amusing the neighborhood with his sleight of hand.
用他的技巧取悦邻居
- Don't tell me that. - It's too obvious and stupid a way to commit murder.
- 我才不信 - 这样杀人太明目张胆了
In full view of 50 windows?
在50个窗口的注视下？
Then sit there smoking a cigar, waiting for the police to come and pick him up?
然后坐下来抽雪茄，等警察来抓他
All right, officer, do your duty. Go over and pick him up.
好吧，警官，尽你的职责，去抓他吧
Jeff, you've got a lot to learn about homicide.
杰夫，你太不了解杀人犯了
Morons have committed murder so shrewdly...
为了抓住杀人犯摩伦
it's taken a hundred trained police minds to catch them.
我们动用了超过100个训练有素的警察
That salesman wouldn't just knock his wife off after dinner...
那推销员不会在晚饭后打昏妻子
and toss her in the trunk and put her in storage.
把她扔进箱子藏起来
I'll bet it's been done.
我打赌他已经这么做了
Most everything's been done, under panic.
所有凶手做案后都会惊慌失措
This is a thousand-to-one shot.
例外的概率只有千分之一
He's still sitting around the apartment. That man's not panicked.
可他还坐着那，一点儿也不惊慌
You think I made all this up?
你觉得这都是我编的？
Well, I think you saw something...
我觉得你所看到的一切
there's probably a very simple explanation for.
很容易解释
- For instance? - Wife took a trip.
-比方说？ -妻子去旅行了
His wife was sick in bed.
他妻子有病在床
Yeah, so you told me.
对，你说过
Well, Jeff, I've got to run along.
呃，杰夫，我得走了
I won't report this to the department.
我不会向上面报告
Let me poke into it a little on my own.
我会私下调查一下
- No sense in your getting a lot of ridiculous publicity. - Thank you.
- 免得你又写些荒唐报道 - 多谢
We know the wife is gone.
他妻子不见了
- I'll see if I can find out where. - Do that.
- 看能不能找到她 - 一定要找
You had any headaches lately?
你最近有头痛吗？
Not until you showed up.
见到你之后才有
It will wear off, along with the hallucinations.
会好的，等你的幻觉消失后
See you around.
再见
Get along.
去吧
He has a six months' lease. Used up a little more than five and a half months of it.
他的公寓租期六个月，已经住五个半月了
He's quiet, drinks, but not to drunkenness.
不太健谈，喝酒，但从不喝醉
Pays his bills promptly with money earned as a costume jewelry salesman, wholesale.
准时付账，靠推销和批发人造珠宝为生
Kept to himself. No neighbors got close to him or his wife.
不太交际，邻居与他和他妻子接触不多
Yeah, well, I think they missed their chance with her.
我想他们再也没机会和她接触了
- She never left the apartment, until yesterday morning. - Where is she...
- 她很少离家，不过昨天早上离开了 - 她在哪儿？
- What time? - 6:00 a.m.
- 什么时间？ - 早上六点
6:00 a.m.
早上6:00
I think that's about the time I fell asleep.
我猜我正好睡着了
Too bad. Thorwalds were leaving their apartment at just that time.
太糟了，当时索沃德夫妇正离开
Feel a little foolish?
觉得自己有点傻？
Oh, not yet.
还没有
How's your wife?
你妻子还好吗？
Oh, she's fine.
噢，她很好
Who said they left then?
谁说他们那时离开了？
- W-Who left where? - The Thorwalds at 6:00 in the morning.
- 谁，离开哪？ - 索沃德夫妇，早上六点
Oh, the building superintendent and two tenants.
噢，大厦管理员和两个房客
Flat statements, no hesitation. They jibe to the letter.
而且脱口而出，说法完全一致
Thorwalds were on their way to the railroad station.
他们去了火车站
Well now, Tom, how could anybody possibly guess that?
汤姆，人们怎会那样猜想？
What, did they have signs on their luggage saying, "Grand Central or bust?"
难道他们行李上写着去火车站吗？
The superintendent met Thorwald on his way back.
管理员在他回来时碰上他了
Thorwald told him that he'd put his wife on a train to the country.
他说送妻子去了乡下
I see. I'd say this is a pretty convenient guy, this superintendent.
我明白了，这个管理员可真容易利用
Have you checked his bank statements lately? - Huh?
- 有查过他最近的银行帐户吗？- 啊？
Well, what good's his information?
这些消息有什么用？
It's a secondhand version of an unsupported story by the murderer himself.
都是凶手编造的对自己有利的二手信息
Now did anybody actually see the wife get on the train?
有人看到他妻子上火车了吗？
I hate to remind you, but this all started because you said she was murdered.
我得提醒你，你说她被害了
Now did anyone, including you, actually see her murdered?
但有任何人，包括你在内看到她被害了吗？
What are you doing?
你…你在干什么？
Are you interested in solving this case or in making me look foolish?
你到底是想破这个案子，还是想嘲笑我？
Well, if possible, both.
呃，可能二者兼有之
Then do a good job of it. Go over there and search Thorwald's apartment.
那么动手吧，去搜搜他的公寓
- It must be knee-deep in evidence. - I can't do that.
- 肯定会有确凿的证据 - 我做不到
I don't mean right now, but when he goes out for a drink or a paper.
我不是说现在，等他出去喝酒或买报时候
What he doesn't know won't hurt him.
对他也没坏处
I can't do that even if he isn't there.
他不在时也不行
What's he...
Does he have a courtesy card from the police department or something?
难道他有警察局的优待券吗？
Now don't get me mad.
你快让我发疯了
Not even a detective can walk into an apartment and search it.
即使探长也不能随便搜查别人的公寓
If I were caught in there, they'd have my badge within ten minutes.
如果我被发现，十分钟内就会被撤职
Make sure you don't get caught, that's all.
那就别让人发现
If you find something, you've got a murderer, and they don't care anything about house rules.
如果找到证据，你就抓到一个凶手，他们才不在乎搜查的事呢
If you don't find anything, the fellow's clear.
如果没找到，那人就是清白的
At the risk of sounding stuffy, I'd like to remind you of the Constitution...
虽然很乏味，但我还是要提醒你宪法规定...
and the phrase, "search warrant issued by a judge" who knows his Bill of Rights verbatim.
只有法官有权派发搜查令
He must ask for evidence.
他必须要有证据
Give him evidence.
给他证据
Yeah, I can hear myself,
像这样？
"Your Honor, I have a friend who's an amateur sleuth.
“大人，我有个朋友是业余侦探”
The other night, after having a heavy dinner, he..."
“一天晚饭吃多了，
He'd throw the New York State penal code in my face, and it's six volumes.
他说纽约州的刑法是狗屁”
By tomorrow morning, there may not be any evidence left over in that apartment.
你知道，到明天早上，可能什么证据都不剩了
- You know that. - It's a detective's nightmare.
- 你明白的 - 那是侦探的噩梦
What do you need before you can search?
到底要怎么样，你才肯去搜查？
Tell me now, what do you need? Bloody footsteps leading up to the door?
告诉我，要怎么样，一定要鲜血四溅吗？
One thing I don't need is heckling. You called me and asked for help.
我不想被质问，是你打电话找我帮忙
Now you're behaving like a taxpayer.
现在却苛刻得像个纳税人
How did we ever stand each other in that plane for three years during the war?
在战争中，我们怎么在那架飞机上彼此忍受三年的？
I guess I'll go over to the railroad station, check on Thorwald's story.
我还是去火车站看看得了
Forget about the story. Find the trunk. Mrs. Thorwald's in it.
算了吧，去找那箱子，索沃德太太在里面
Oh, I almost forgot. There was a postcard in Thorwald's mailbox.
差点忘了，他家的信箱中有封明信片
It was mailed 3:30 yesterday afternoon from Merritsville.
是昨天下午3:30从梅利斯维尔寄来的
That's 80 miles north of here.
离这儿有80英里远
The message went: "Arrived okay.
上面说：“安全到达，
Already feeling better. Love, Anna."
觉得好多了，爱你的安娜”
Uh... is that, um...
安娜，就是，是…
Anna... Is that who I think it is?
额...是像我认为的那样吗？
- Mrs. Thorwald. - Uh-huh.
- 索沃德太太
Oh, so anything you need, Jeff?
哦，你还需要什么吗，杰夫？
You might send me a good detective.
你最好送个好探长来
- Oh, by the way, where's the gin? - I'll get the gin.
- 噢，对了，杜松子酒在哪儿？ - 我去拿
Much faster, and swing the left arm up.
快了点，把左臂抬高
Many dreams ago
Try it again.
再来一次
I dreamed many dreams
Waiting for
My true love
To appear
Though each night
It seems
Someone filled
My dreams
Still the face that I kissed
Wasn't clear
So I let my heart dance
Through many sweet refrains
But now just one song
And just one dream remains
That one song is you
And at last I know
You're the one I dreamed of
Many dreams ago
- Hello. Yes. - Hello, Miss Doyle?
- 喂 - 喂，多尤太太吗？
- This is Jeff again. Has Tom come in yet? - Not yet, Jeff.
- 是的 -还是我，杰夫，汤姆回来了吗？- 还没有，杰夫
- You mean you haven't even heard from him? - Not a word.
- 他也没打电话回来吗？ - 没有
- Is it something really important, Jeff? - I'm afraid it is, Tess.
- 有什么重要的事吗，杰夫？ - 恐怕是的，苔丝
I'll have him call the moment I hear from him.
我一联系上他，就让他打电话给你
No, don't bother to do that. Just have him get over here as soon as he can.
不必了，让他尽快来我这儿
- Looks like Thorwald's pulling out tonight. - Who's Thorwald?
- 看样子索沃德打算今晚逃跑 - 谁是索沃德？
He'll know, he'll know. And Thorwald's a man, Tess. Don't worry.
他会明白的，索沃德是个男人，苔丝，别担心
Good night, you idiot.
晚安,你这傻瓜[笑]
Good night.
晚安
Long distance again.
又是长途电话
There's somebody at the door. Who's at the door?
有人敲门，是谁？
- Hi.
- 你好
Hello.
你好
- What'd you do to your hair? - Oh, I just...
- 你头发怎么了？ - 我…
Take a look at Thorwald. He's getting ready to pull out for good. Look at him.
看看索沃德先生，他正准备逃跑
He doesn't seem to be in any hurry.
他好像不太着急
He's been laying out all his things on one of the beds:
他已经把东西都放在床上了
shirts, suits, coats, socks.
衬衫，西装，外套，袜子
- Even that alligator handbag his wife left on the bedpost. - What about it?
- 还有他妻子留在床头的鳄鱼皮手提包 - 包在哪？
He had it hidden in the dresser. At least, it was there.
他藏在梳妆台里，之前一直在那
He took it out, went to the telephone and made a long-distance call.
他刚才把它拿了出来，打了个长途电话
He had his wife's jewelry in the handbag.
包里有他妻子的手饰
Seemed worried about it. Asked someone's advice over the telephone.
看起来他有些担心，打电话找人商量
- Someone not his wife. - Well, I never saw him ask her for advice.
- 那人肯定不是他妻子. - 对，我从未见过他找妻子商量
She volunteered plenty, but I never saw him ask her for any.
她到是很主动，但他从不找她
- I wonder where he's going. - I don't know.
- 他会去哪儿？ - 不知道
- Suppose he doesn't come back? - He'll be back. His things are still there.
- 万一他不回来呢？ - 不会的，他的东西还在
- I guess it's safe to put on some lights now. - No, not yet.
- 我想现在可以开灯了 - 不，等一会
Okay, you can turn it on now. He must have gone someplace to the right.
好的，开吧，他往右边去了
All day long, I've been trying to keep my mind on my work.
我一整天都没法集中精力工作
Thinking about Thorwald?
想着索沃德的事？
And you and your friend, Doyle.
还有你和你的朋友多尤
- Did you hear from him again since he left? - Not a word.
- 有他的消息吗？ - 没有
He said he was gonna check the railroad station and the trunk.
他去查火车站和箱子了
He must be still at it.
大概还没忙完
Something on your mind?
你在想什么？
- It doesn't make sense to me. - What doesn't?
- 这很不对劲 - 什么？
Women aren't that unpredictable.
女人不会这么粗心
Hmm. Well, I can't guess what you're thinking.
我不明白你的意思
A woman has a favorite handbag,
一个女人很喜欢她的手提包
and it always hangs on her bedpost where she can get at it easily.
总是把它带在身边
Then, all of a sudden, she goes away on a trip and leaves it behind. Why?
有一天她出远门，却没带它，为什么？
Because she didn't know she was going on a trip,
因为她不知道自己要出远门
and where she's going, she wouldn't need the handbag.
或者她要去的地方不需要带包
Yes, but only her husband would know that.
对，可他丈夫知道
And that jewelry... Women don't keep their jewelry in a purse
还有手饰，女人不会把手饰胡乱堆放在包中
getting all twisted and scratched and tangled up.
- Well, do they hide it in their husband's clothes? - They do not.
- 那放在丈夫衣服里？ - 不会
And they don't leave it behind either.
而且她们不会把手饰放在家里的
Why, a woman going anywhere but the hospital would always take makeup, perfume and jewelry.
除了上医院，女人都要化妆，喷香水，戴手饰的
Put that over there. That's inside stuff, huh?
放那儿，这是你们的内部秘密？
It's basic equipment.
这是基本的要求
And you don't leave it behind in your husband's drawer in your favorite handbag.
绝不会放在手提包里，留在丈夫的抽屉中
I'm with you, sweetie. I'm with you.
我也很怀疑，亲爱的
Tom Doyle has a pat answer for that though.
但汤姆.多尤说…
That Mrs. Thorwald left yesterday with her husband?
说索沃德太太昨天早上和她丈夫一起离开的？
According to those witnesses.
目击者说的
Well, I have a pat rebuttal for Mr. Doyle.
我听多尤先生说过了
- Couldn't have been Mrs. Thorwald, or I don't know women. - Oh?
- 那肯定不是索沃德太太 - 真的？
- What about the witnesses?
怎么解释目击者呢？
We'll agree they saw a woman,
他们确实见到一个女人
but she was not Mrs. Thorwald.
可那不是索沃德太太
That is, not yet.
不是她本人
Is that so?
是吗？
Come here.
过来
I'd like to see your friend's face when we tell him.
真想看看你朋友听到这些后的表情
He doesn't sound like much of a detective.
他可不太像个探长
Oh, don't be too hard on him. He's a steady worker.
别难为他，他是个老实的公务员
I sure wish he'd show up.
真希望他快点到
Don't rush him. We have all night.
别着急，我们有一整晚的时间
- We have all what? - Night.
- 有什么？ - 整晚
I am going to stay with you.
我会留下陪你
You'll have to clear that with my landlord.
那你得和我的房东说清楚
I have the whole weekend off.
我整个周末都不用上班
That's very nice, but I just have one bed.
很好，可我只有一张床
If you say anything else, I'll... stay tomorrow night too.
你再说话，明晚我也住这儿
I won't be able to give you any... pajamas.
我没有多的…睡衣给你
You said I'll have to live out of one suitcase.
你说过，野外生存只能带一个箱子
I'll bet yours isn't this small.
我打赌，你的肯定比这个大
This is a suitcase?
这是个衣箱？
Well, a Mark Cross overnight case anyway.
“马克.克洛斯”牌短途旅行箱
- Ooh, wow. - Compact, but, uh... ample enough.
- 噢 - 小巧紧凑，但足够用了
Looks like you packed in a hurry.
你好像收拾得很匆忙
Look at this. Isn't that amazing?
这个很有意思
I'll trade you... my feminine intuition for a bed for the night.
为了奖励我的女性直觉，留我过夜如何？
I'll go along with that.
我同意
There's that song again.
又是那首曲子
Where does a man get inspiration to write a song like that?
他哪来的灵感，能写出这样的曲子？
Well, he gets it from the landlady once a month.
每个月从房东太太那儿得到的
It's utterly beautiful.
真是太美了
I wish I could be creative.
真希望我也有创作才能
Oh, sweetie, you are.
噢，亲爱的，你有
Y-Y-You have a great talent for creating difficult situations.
你在制造麻烦方面很有天赋
- I do? - Sure. Staying here all night, uninvited.
- 真的？- 当然. 不请自来，还擅自留下过夜
Surprise is the most important element of attack.
出其不意，攻其不备
Besides, you're not up on your private eye literature.
你没读过那本私家侦探小说吗？
When they're in trouble, it's always their Girl Friday who gets them out of it.
当他们有麻烦时，总是女助手帮侦探摆脱困境
Is she the girl that saves them from the clutches of the seductive showgirls...
也是她把他从艳舞女郎
and the over-passionate daughters of the rich?
还有富翁女儿的魔爪下救出来的？
- The same. - That's the one, huh?
- 就是那一部 - 就是那一部，啊
It's funny. He never ends up marrying her, does he?
有趣，可他俩从未结婚，是吗？
- That's strange. - Weird.
- 真奇怪 - 奇怪
Why don't I slip into something more comfortable?
我为何不钻进更舒服点的地方？
By all means.
请便
I mean, like the kitchen and make us some coffee.
比如去厨房煮点咖啡
Oh, and some brandy too, huh?
还有白兰地
Harry.
哈利
- Jeff. - Hi.
- 杰夫 - 嗨
What else have you got on this man Thorwald?
你对这个索沃德还知道些什么？
Enough to scare me you wouldn't show up in time and we'd lose him.
很多，你再不来，他就跑了
Think he's getting out of here? He's got everything he owns...
他要离开？
laid out over there in the bedroom, waiting to be packed.
他已经在床上收拾行李了
I'm just warming some brandy. Mr. Doyle, I presume?
我正在热白兰地，我猜这就是多尤先生
Tom, this is Miss Lisa Fremont.
汤姆，这是丽莎.弗里蒙特小姐
- How do you do? - We think Thorwald's guilty.
-你好 -我们认为索沃德有罪
Careful, Tom.
别瞎猜，汤姆
Hello.
喂
- Lieutenant Doyle. - Yeah, he's right here. For you.
-多尤中尉在吗？ -对，他在，找你的
- Hello. - Lieutenant Doyle, sir?
-你好 -多尤中尉吗？
Speaking. Yeah.
对，你说吧，好
All right. I see. Thank you. Good-bye.
好的，我知道了，多谢，再见
Coffee will be ready soon.
咖啡很快就好
- Jeff, aren't you going to tell him about the jewelry? - Jewelry?
- 杰夫，为什么不告诉他手饰的事？- 手饰？
He's got his wife's jewelry hidden in his clothes in the bedroom there.
他把妻子的手饰藏在卧室的衣服里
You sure it belonged to his wife?
你确定是他妻子的？
It was in her favorite handbag.
在她最喜欢的手提包里
- Mr. Doyle, that can only lead to one conclusion. - Namely?
- 多尤先生，这只能得出一个结论 - 什么？
That it was not Mrs. Thorwald that left with him yesterday morning.
昨天早上离开的不是索沃德太太
You figured that out, eh?
你怎么知道？
It's simply that women don't leave their jewelry behind when they go on a trip.
很简单，女人不会不带手饰去旅行
Come on, Tom. You don't really need any of this information, do you?
噢，汤姆，你早知道了对不对？
As a matter of fact, I don't.
的确
Lars Thorwald is no more a murderer than I am.
拉兹.索沃德不是杀人犯
You can explain everything that's going on over there and is still going on?
你能解释这里发生的一切？
No, neither can you.
不能，你也不能
That's a secret, private world you're looking into out there.
你看到的是别人的私生活
People do a lot of things in private they couldn't possibly explain in public.
人们的隐私很难在公开场合下解释
Like disposing of their wives?
例如谋杀妻子？
Get that idea out of your mind. It'll only lead in the wrong direction.
忘掉这想法吧，那只会引出错误结论
What about the knife and the saw?
怎么解释刀和锯子呢？
Did you ever own a saw?
你自己有锯子吗？
Well, at home in the garage, I had...
有，在车库里，我有…
How many people did you cut up with it?
你用它杀了多少人？
Or with the couple hundred knives you've owned in your lifetime?
你这辈子用过多少刀？
Your logic is backward.
不能就凭这些作出判断
You can't ignore the disappearance and the trunk and the jewelry.
可妻子失踪了，还有箱子和手饰怎么解释？
I checked the railroad station. He bought a ticket.
我查过火车站，他买了张票
Ten minutes later, he put his wife on the train.
十点钟后，他送妻子上了火车
Destination: Merritsville. The witnesses are that deep.
目的地：梅利斯维尔.目击者堆成山
That might have been a woman, but it couldn't have been Mrs. Thorwald.
那可能是另一个女人，而不是索沃德太太
- That jewelry... - Miss Fremont, that feminine intuition stuff sells magazines,
-那些手饰… -瞧，弗里蒙特小姐，靠女性直觉破案的故事是能提高杂志销量
but in real life, it's still a fairy tale.
可在现实生活里，那行不通
I don't know how many wasted years I've spent, tracking down leads based on female intuition.
我记不清浪费了多少时间，追查靠女性直觉提供的线索
All right, I take it you didn't find the trunk.
够了，我知道你没找到箱子
All this is from an old speech you made at the policemen's ball.
别背诵你在警局用过的发言稿了
I found the trunk a half-hour after I left here.
离开火车站一个半小时后，我找到了箱子
I suppose it's normal for a man to tie up a trunk with heavy rope?
难道用绳子绑箱子正常吗？
If the lock is broken, yes.
若锁坏了，就正常
What did you find inside the trunk, a surly note to me?
你在箱子里找到了什么？ 傲慢的语气
Mrs. Thorwald's clothes;
索沃德太太的衣服
clean, well-packed, not stylish, but presentable.
干净，整齐，不太时髦，但还拿得出手
Didn't you take them off to the crime lab?
你没送去实验室化验
I sent them on their merry and legal way.
我送去了
Why, when a woman is taking a simple, short trip,
为什么一个短途旅行的女人
does she take everything she owns?
要带上所有的东西？
Let's let the female psychology department handle that one.
这个问题还是留给女性心理分析专家来解释吧
I would say it looked as if she wasn't coming back.
也许她不打算回来了
That's what's known as a family problem.
这就是所谓的家庭纠纷
If she wasn't coming back, why didn't he tell his landlord?
如果她不回来了，为什么不告诉房东？
I'll tell you why he didn't tell his landlord, because he was hiding something.
我告诉你为什么，因为他隐藏了什么
Do you tell your landlord everything?
你什么事都告诉房东吗？
Ah, I told you to be careful, Tom.
我说过小心点，别瞎猜，汤姆
If I'd have been careful piloting that recognizance plane during the war,
如果那次作战时，我小心点开飞机
you wouldn't have had the chance to take the pictures
你就不会碰巧拍到获奖照片,
that won you a medal and a good job and fame and money.
找到好工作,名利双收
What do you say, we all sit down and have a nice friendly drink or two?
不如我们坐下来好好喝两杯吧
Forget all about this.
忘了这一切吧
We can tell lies about the good old days during the war.
我们可以随便聊聊当兵时的好时光
You mean you're through with the case?
你对这案子了如指掌了？
There is no case to be through with, Miss Fremont. How about that drink?
根本就没有什么案子，弗里蒙特小姐，再来一杯吧
Yeah, I guess you're right.
好吧
I think I better get home and get some sleep.
呃，我想我该回家睡觉了
Cheers.
干杯
I, uh... I'm not much of a snifter.
我有点不胜酒力
Oh, Jeff, if you need any more help...
噢，杰夫，如果需要帮助，就查黄页本吧
consult the Yellow Pages in your telephone directory.
Oh, I love funny exiting lines.
我喜欢滑稽的退场台词
Who was that trunk addressed to?
那箱子是寄给谁的？
Mrs. Anna Thorwald.
安娜.索沃德太太
Then let's wait and find out who picks it up.
那么我们查查是谁领取的？
Oh, that telephone call... I gave them your number. Hope you don't mind.
噢，刚才那个电话… 我把你电话号码留给了他们，希望你不介意
Depends on who they were.
得看他们是谁？
The police at Merritsville. They reported the trunk was just picked up...
梅利斯维尔的警察
他们说箱子刚被安娜.
by Mrs. Anna Thorwald.
索沃德太太领走了
Don't stay up too late.
别熬得太晚了
- Look. - What?
-看 -什么？
He's kind of young, isn't he?
他很年轻，不是吗？
What are you doing?
你干什么？
Orjust a cold and lonely
Lovely work of art
You know, much as I hate to give Thomas J. Doyle too much credit,
你知道，我不是不愿相信多尤的话
he might have gotten ahold of something when he said...
他说这只是别人的隐私，
that was pretty private stuff going on out there.
确实有些道理
I wonder if it's ethical to watch a man...
我怀疑用望远镜观察别人是否道德？
with binoculars and a long-focus lens.
Do you...
Do you suppose it's ethical, even if you prove that he didn't commit a crime?
仅仅因为我们证明他是清白的，就情有可原吗?
I'm not much on rear window ethics.
我不知道
Of course, they can do the same thing to me, watch me like a bug under a glass if they want to.
当然，他们也可以观察我，就像看玻璃杯下面的小虫子
Jeff, you know if someone came in here, they wouldn't believe what they'd see.
杰夫，如果有人进来，他们不会相信所见到的一切
- What? - You and me with long faces, plunged into despair...
-见到什么？ -我们俩拉长了脸，失望沮丧
because we find out a man didn't kill his wife.
因为我们发现一个男人没有杀害他妻子
We're two of the most frightening ghouls I've ever known.
我们真是两个冷血动物
You'd think we could be a little bit happy the poor woman is alive and well.
那可怜的女人还活着，我们应高兴点
Whatever happened to that old saying, "Love the neighbor?"
那句老话怎么说的：“爱你的邻居”？
You know, I think I'll start reviving that tomorrow.
[笑]我明天就去实践这句话
Yeah, I'll begin with Miss Torso.
对，先从多索小姐开始
Not if I have to move into an apartment across the way...
那我也搬到对面去
and do the Dance of the Seven Veils every hour.
每天跳肚皮舞
Show's over for tonight.
今晚的演出结束了
Preview of coming attractions.
先让你饱饱眼福
Did Mr. Doyle think I stole this case?
多尤先生怀疑这箱子是我偷来的？
No, Lisa, I don't think he did.
不，丽莎，我想他没有
- What do you think? - Well, uh...
- 你觉得怎么样？ - 呃…
- I will rephrase the question. - Thank you.
- 那我换个问法 - 谢谢
Do you like it?  Yes,I like it.
- 你喜欢吗？ - 是的，我喜欢
What's the matter?
怎么了？
- Somebody's hurt? - It's the dog.
- 有人受伤了？ - 是狗
Something's happened to the dog.
小狗出事了
- Somebody fall out a window? - I don't know.
- 有人坠楼了？ - 不知道
I think it's a dog.
好像是狗
It's dead. It's been strangled. The neck is broken.
它死了，是被掐死的，脖子都断了
Which one of you did it? Which one of you killed my dog?
是谁干的？是谁害死我的小狗？
You don't know the meaning of the word neighbor!
远亲不如近邻
Neighbors like each other,
邻居应该互敬互爱
speak to each other, care if anybody lives or dies!
互相倾述，互相关心，在乎别人的生活
But none of you do!
难道你们不明白？
But I couldn't imagine any of you being so low that you'd kill a little helpless, friendly dog.
想不到你们会杀死一只友善无辜的小狗
The only thing in this whole neighborhood who liked anybody!
只有它喜欢这儿的所有人
Did you kill him because he liked you? Just because he liked you?
你杀死它，就因为它喜欢你？
Let's go inside.
进去吧
Come on. Let's go back in. It's only a dog.
回去吧，只是一条狗
You know, for a minute, that Tom Doyle almost had me convinced I was wrong.
你知道，刚才汤姆.多尤差点就让我认为自己错了
- But you're not? - Look.
-你没有吗？ -看
In the courtyard, only one person didn't come to the window. Look.
整个院子里，只有一个人没走到窗边，看
Why would Thorwald want to kill a little dog?
索沃德为什么要杀一只小狗？
Because it knew too much?
因它知道的太多？
You think this is worth waiting all day to see?
你们觉得这值得等一整天吗？
Is he cleaning house?
他在清扫房间吗？
He's washing down the bathroom walls.
他在清洗洗手间的墙壁
Hmm, must have splattered a lot.
嗯，血一定溅得到处都是
Well, why not? That's what we're all thinking.
怎么啦？我们不就是这么想的吗？
He killed her in there, he has to clean up those stains.
他在那儿杀了她，离开前要清理现场
Oh, Stella, your choice of words.
噢，斯泰拉，看你说的
Nobody ever invented a polite word for a killing yet.
杀人还有什么好听的说法？
Lisa, back there on that shelf, there's a little yellow box. You see it?
丽莎，后面架子上有个小黄盒子，看见了吗？
- Top one? - Right on top, yeah.
-最上面？ -在右上边，对
And bring me the viewer there.
把看片器拿给我
I just got a... These are about two weeks old.
我刚刚…这些是两周前拍的
I hope I took something else besides leg art.
希望我拍的东西有用，
- Now which one... - What are you looking for?
- 哪一张 - 你找什么？
I'm looking for something and if I'm right, I think I've solved a murder.
如果没错的话，我想我可以找出凶手
- Mrs. Thorwald? - No.
- 杀人凶手？ - 不是
No, the dog. Uh-huh.
不，是杀狗的凶手
I think I know why Thorwald killed that dog.
我明白他为什么要杀狗了
Here, now you take a look. Tell me what you see.
你看，告诉我你看到什么？
Now take it down. Now look again.
把它移下来，再看一下，
Now take it down. You see?
移下来，看到了？
It's just a picture of the backyard, that's all.
只是后院的照片
One important change. One important change.
有个重要的变化
Those flowers in Thorwald's pet flower bed.
是花坛里的花
You mean where the dog was sniffing around?
你指狗在花坛中找什么？
Where the dog was digging. Now look at those flowers.
狗一直在挖那儿，看那些花
Look, those two yellow zinnias on this end...
看，那两朵黄色的百日菊，在边上…
aren't as tall as they were.
没有以前高了.
Since when do flowers grow shorter in two weeks?
什么时候开始花越长越矮了？
There's something buried there.
下面埋着东西
Mrs. Thorwald.
索沃德太太
You haven't spent much time around cemeteries, have you?
你最近很少去上坟吧？
Mr. Thorwald could scarcely put his wife's body...
他绝不可能把妻子埋在一尺见方的地方
in a plot of ground about one foot square.
Unless, of course, he put her in standing on end.
除非他把她竖着埋下去
Then he wouldn't need a knife and saw.
如果那样，他就不需刀和锯子了
No, my idea is she's scattered all over town. Leg in the East River...
不，我看她已经被扔得遍布满城了
- Oh, Stella, please. - No, there's something in there though.
-腿在东河里… -噢，斯泰拉，够了
Those flowers have been taken out and put back in.
不，有东西在那儿，花被挖出来又栽回去
- Maybe it's the knife and saw. - Yeah...
- 可能是刀和锯子 - 也许
- Call Lieutenant Doyle. - No, let's wait.
- 通知多尤中尉吧 - 不，等一下
Let's wait till it gets a little darker,
等天黑一点，
and I'll go over there and dig them up.
我去挖
You'll go? You won't dig anything up and get your neck broken.
你去？你还没开挖，脖子就断了.
No, we've...
I'm not gonna call Doyle until I can produce Mrs. Thorwald's body.
我不会通知多尤，除非找到尸体
What we've got to do is find a way to get into that apartment.
我们要做的是，到他公寓里去…
He's packing.
他在收拾东西
Uh-oh.
Here, get me a pencil.
拿着，给我支笔
Stella, get me some note paper. It's up here someplace.
斯泰拉，拿张信笺纸，在那上面，好的
There it is.
[拉兹.索沃德 你对她做了些什么？]
You did it, Thorwald. You did it.
是你干的，索沃德，是你干的
Look out, Lisa. He's coming. Look.
当心，丽莎，他来了
You never should have let her do it.
你不该让她去的
Thank heaven that's over.
啊，感谢老天，总算完了
- All right if I have a drink? - Sure, go ahead.
-可以喝一杯吗？ -当然，请便
There's no doubt about it, he's leaving.
毫无疑问，他想跑了
It's just a question of when.
只是时间问题
Mind if I use that portable keyhole?
我可以看一下那个“移动钥匙孔”[指相机]吗？
Go ahead, just as long as you tell me...
给你，告诉我看你到什么了？
what you're looking at.
- I wonder... - You wonder what?
- 奇怪 - 奇怪什么？
Miss Lonelyhearts just laid out something that looks like...
单身小姐像是要吃安眠药
rodium tri-eckonal capsules.
- You can tell from here? - I've handled enough of those red pills...
- 你看清楚了吗？ - 我吃过那种药
to put everybody in Hackensack to sleep for the winter.
那些药可让人睡上一个冬天
- Does she have enough of them to... - It'll make the rest...
- 她有足够的… - 我再看看…
Wasn't that close?
很险吧
What was his reaction when he looked at the note?
他有什么反应？我指看了纸条后
It wasn't the kind of expression that would get him a quick loan at the bank.
反正不是从银行得到贷款的表情
Jeff, the handbag!
杰夫，那手提包
Suppose Mrs. Thorwald's wedding ring...
假如索沃德太太的结婚戒指在手提包里
is among the jewelry he has in that handbag?
During the phone conversation he held up three rings:
他打电话时拿出了三个戒指
one with a diamond, one with a big stone of some sort,
有一个是带钻石的，有一个是宝石的
and then just a plain gold band.
还有一个是金的
The last thing she would leave behind...
她绝不会把结婚戒指留在家里
would be her wedding ring.
Stella, do you ever leave yours at home?
斯泰拉，你会把结婚戒指忘在家里吗？
The only way anybody could get that ring would be to chop off my finger.
除非有人切断我的手指
Let's go down and find out what's buried in the garden.
我们去看看花坛里埋的是什么吧
Why not? I've always wanted to meet Mrs. Thorwald.
为何不呢？我一直想见见索沃德太太
- What are you two talking about... - You got a shovel?
- 你们俩在说什么？ - 有铲子吗？
- Of course I don't have a shovel. - Probably one in the basement.
- 当然没有 - 地下室可能有
If you're squeamish, just don't look.
-等等 -杰夫，如果你觉得恶心，就别看
I'm not squeamish. I just don't want you two to end up like that dog.
我才不怕？我只是不想看到你俩与小狗一样下场
Oh, you know, Miss Fremont, he might just have something there.
一定有东西的
Just hold on. Here, take this.
先等等，拿着，
No sense taking any chances in this thing.
为这事冒险不值得
Give me the phone book.
把电话本给我
- What for? - Maybe I can get him out of that apartment.
- 干什么？ - 也许我可以把他从公寓里弄出来
We only need a few minutes.
我们只需几分钟
I'll see if I can get about 15 minutes.
最好能有一刻钟
- How? - Thorwald.
- 怎么做？ - 索沃德
Thorwald.Thorwald.
Chelsea 2-7099.
切尔西 2-7099
2-7099.
We scared him once, maybe we can scare him again.
也许我们可以再吓他一次
I guess I'm using that word "we" a little freely.
也许说“我们”不恰当.
You're taking all the chances.
一切都看你们的了
- Shall we vote him in, Stella? - Unanimously.
-要让他加入吗，斯泰拉？ -全票通过
2-7099. Look out.
2-7099，小心点，切尔西
Chelsea.
Go on, pick it up, Thorwald.
快点，接电话，索沃德
Go on, you're curious.
来吧，你很好奇
You wonder if it's your girlfriend calling, the one you killed for.
也许是你的女伴打来的，你为她杀了人
Go on, pick it up.
快接
- Hello? - Did you get my note?
-喂 -收到我的信了吗？
Well, did you get it, Thorwald?
你收到了吗，索沃德？
- Who are you? - I'll give you a chance to find out.
-你是谁？ -我会让你知道的
Meet me in the bar at the Albert Hotel.
在阿尔伯特饭店的酒吧等我，现在就去
Do it right away.
为什么？
- Why should I? - A little business meeting...
有点事要谈
to settle the estate of your late wife.
关于如何处理你过世妻子的遗产
I... don't know what you mean.
我不懂你的意思
Quit stalling, Thorwald,
别装蒜了，索沃德，
or I'll hang up and call the police.
否则我报警
I only have a hundred dollars or so.
我只有大约100块
That's a start.
那只是个开始
I'm at the Albert now. I'll be looking for you.
我已经到饭店了，我会等你的
Come on, Stella, let's go.
来吧，斯泰拉，我们动手
One of you keep an eye on this window.
注意看我的窗户
If I see him coming back, I'll signal with a flashbulb.
如果他回来，我会用闪光灯发信号
This is the Doyle residence.
这是多尤家
Hello, this is L.B. Jefferies. I'm a friend of Mr. Doyle.
你好，我是L.B.杰弗利，多尤先生的朋友
- Who's this? - This is a baby-sitter.
-你是谁？ -我是保姆
- Oh, uh, when do you expect them in? - I'm hired till 1:00.
-呃，他们什么时候回来？ -我一点钟回家
- They went to dinner and maybe a nightclub. - I see.
-他们去吃晚餐了，也许在夜总会 -知道了
If he calls in, have him get in touch with L.B. Jefferies?
如果他打电话回来，让他立刻打电话给L.B.杰弗利
I might have quite a surprise for him.
我有个惊喜给他
Well, do we have your number, Mr. Jefferies?
我们有你的号码吗？
- He has it. Good night. - Good night.
- 他有的，晚安 - 晚安
Ah, Stella was wrong about Miss Lonelyhearts.
啊，斯泰拉误会单身小姐了
Lisa, what are you... Don't...
丽莎，你干什么？不…
Don't...
Lisa, what are you doing? Don't go...
丽莎，你干什么？别去…
Li...
Come on, come on! Get out of there!
快，快，离开那儿
She said ring Thorwald's phone the second you see him come back.
她说见索沃德回来，就打他家的电话
I'll ring it right now.
我现在就打
Give her another minute.
不，给她点时间
All right, fellows, let's try it once from the beginning.
好吧，伙计们，我们从头再练一次
Miss Lonelyhearts. Oh, call the police!
单身小姐，噢，快叫警察
- Operator. - Get me the police, sixth precinct.
- 接线员 - 接警察局，第六分局
Yes, sir.
好的
Mr. Jefferies, the music stopped her.
杰夫先生，音乐让她停下来了
What... Lisa...
丽莎，丽莎
Lisa.
Precinct Six, Sergeant Allgood.
第六分局，我是警长
Hello. Look, a man is assaulting a woman at 125 West Ninth Street,
喂，有个男人正在西九街125号行凶
second floor, at the rear.Make it fast!
二楼，背街面，快点
- Your name? - L.B. Jefferies.
- 你的名字 - L.B.杰弗利
- Phone number? - Chelsea 2-5598.
- 电话 - 切尔西 2-5598
The door was open.
门是开着的
Oh...
- I told you... - Oh, no!
- 我说了… - 噢，不
Let go of me! Jeff!
放我走，杰夫，
- Oh, no! - Jeff! Jeff!
- 噢，不 - 杰夫，杰夫
Jeff!
Lisa! Stella, what do we do?
丽莎，斯泰拉，我们怎么办？
- Jeff! Jeff! - Here they come.
- 杰夫，杰夫 - 警察来了
What's she trying to do? Why doesn't she turn him in?
她想干什么？为什么不告发他？
She's a smart girl.
她是个聪明的女孩
"Smart girl?" She'll get herself arrested.
“聪明的女孩”？她会被抓的
It'll get her out of there, won't it?
那样她就可以脱身了
Look, the wedding ring!
看，结婚戒指
Turn off the light! He's seen us!
快关灯，他看到我们了
How long do you think he'll stay there?
你想他还会呆多久？
Unless he's dumber than I think, he won't wait until his lease is up.
除非他比我想得还笨，他不会等着被抓的
Get my billfold out of the drawer in the table there.
把抽屉里的钱夹给我
- What do you need money for? - I'm gonna bail Lisa out of jail.
- 你要钱干什么？ - 我保丽莎出来
You could leave her there till next Tuesday.
你可以让她呆到下周二
Then you could sneak safely away as planned.
这样你就可以按计划悄悄跑掉了
Yeah, let's see, $ 127.
对，我看看，127块
- How much do you need? - Well, this is first offense burglary.
- 需要多少？ - 这是第一次行窃
That's about 250.
大概250块
- Lisa's handbag. - Yeah.
- 丽莎的手提包 - 对
- How much does she have? - Fifty cents.
- 有多少？ - 50美分
- Here, take this. - I got $ 20 or so in my purse.
- 拿上这个 - 我包里还有20元左右
- Give me what you got. - What about the rest?
- 给我. - 剩下的怎么办？
When those cops see Lisa, they'll even contribute. Hurry up.
警察看到丽莎，也会捐助点的.快去
Just a minute. Hurry up!
等一会，快点
- Jefferies. - What is it now?
- 杰弗利 - 又怎么了？
Doyle, I've got something really big for you.
多尤，有重大发现
Why did I have to return your call?
为什么要我回电话？
Don't louse up my night with another mad killer stuffing a grisly trunk...
杰夫，不要告诉我又有什么凶手
Listen to me! Lisa's in jail. She got arrested.
听我说，听我说，丽莎被捕了
- Your Lisa? - My Lisa.
- 你的丽莎？ - 对
You should have seen her. She got into Thorwald's apartment,
你真该亲眼看看，她刚才溜进了索沃德的公寓
but then he came back and the only way I could get her out was to call the police.
但他突然回来，我只能叫警察来
- I told you... - I know. She went in to get evidence,
- 我说过… - 我知道，她去找证据
and she came out with evidence.
而且找到了
- Like what? - Like Mrs. Thorwald's wedding ring. That's like what.
- 例如？ - 例如索沃德太太的结婚戒指
If that woman was alive, she'd be wearing that ring, right?
如果她还活着，应该带着它，不是吗？
- A possibility. - "A possibility?" It's a fact.
- 可能吧 -可能？这是事实
He killed a dog last night because the dog was scratching around in the garden.
他昨晚杀了一条狗，因为狗在花坛里挖东西
You know why? Because he had something buried in that garden that the dog scented.
知道为什么？他在花坛里埋了东西，狗嗅到了
- Like an old ham bone? - I don't know what pet names Thorwald had for his wife.
- 比如说一块干火腿骨头？ - 我不知道
But I'll tell you this: All those trips at night with that metal suitcase...
但我可以告诉你，他雨夜出门，箱子里装着的
He wasn't taking out his possessions,
绝不是推销样品，
because his possessions are still in the apartment.
那些东西还在公寓里
- You think perhaps it was old "ham bone?" - Yep, in sections.
- 也许是干火腿骨头？ - 对，切成一块块的
I'll tell you something else. All the telephone calls he made were long distance.
还有，他打的电话都是长途
If he called his wife long distance on the day she left,after she arrived in Merritsville,
如果他妻子到达梅利斯维尔的当天，他们通了电话
why did she write a card to him saying she arrived in Merritsville?
为什么她还寄明信片报平安？
Why did she do that?
为什么？
Where'd they take Lisa?
他们带丽莎去哪儿了？
Precinct six.
第六分局
I sent somebody over with the bail money.
我叫人去保她了
- Maybe you won't need it. I'll run it down, Jeff. - All right.
- 不必了，我会处理的 - 好的
Hurry up, will you? This fellow knows he's being watched.
快点，这家伙知道被监视了
He's not gonna wait around forever. Hurry up.
他不会坐以待毙的，快点
- If that ring checks out, we'll give him an escort. So long, Jeff. - So long.
- 如果长途电话属实，我们会逮捕他的，再见，杰夫 - 再见
Hello, Tom. I think Thorwald's left. I don't see...
喂，汤姆，我想索沃德跑了，我没看见…
Hello?
喂？
What do you want from me?
你想怎么样？
Your friend, the girl, could have turned me in. Why didn't she?
你的朋友，那女孩，本来可以告发我，为什么她不说？
What is it you want, a lot of money? I don't have any money.
你想要什么？要钱吗？我没钱
Say something.
说话呀
Say something! Tell me what you want!
说话呀，你要什么？
Can you get me that ring back?
能把戒指还给我吗？
- No. - Tell her to bring it back.
- 不 - 让她拿回来
I can't. The police have it by now.
不行，现在在警察那儿
Lisa! Doyle!
丽莎！多尤！
What was that?
出什么事了？
Look! Look over at that apartment! They're fighting!
看，在那，他们打起来了
Look, he's throwing him out the window!
看，他要把他扔出窗外了
Doyle!
多尤
Creele, give me your.38!
克里尔，把枪给我
I'm sorry, Jeff. I got here as fast as I could.
对不起，杰夫，我来晚了
Mr. Jefferies... Don't let anybody touch him. Get my medical bag upstairs.
别碰着他，把我楼上的药箱拿来
- Lisa, sweetie, if anything had happened to you... - Oh, shut up.
- 丽莎，亲爱的，如果你出了事… - 噢，别说了，我没事
I'm all right. Gee, I'm proud of you.
我以你为荣
You got enough for a search warrant now?
现在可以下搜查令了吧？
- Oh, yeah, sure. - Lieutenant Doyle?
- 噢，当然 - 多尤中尉
- Yeah? - Is he okay?
-什么 -他没事吧？
- He's alive. - Thorwald's ready to take us on a tour of the East River.
- 还活着. - 索沃德要带我们去游东河了
Did he say what was buried in the flower bed?
他说了花坛里埋了什么吗？
Yeah. He said the dog got too inquisitive, so he dug it up.
说了，他说小狗太好奇了，所以把它挖起来了
It's in a hat box over in his apartment.
现在 在公寓里的帽盒里
- You want look? - No, thanks.
- 想看吗？ - 不，谢谢
I don't want any part of her.
一块也不想看
I hope it's gonna be a hit. This is the first release.
希望会成功，这是第一版
I'd love to hear it.
我很想听
I can't tell you what this music has meant to me.
这曲子对我来说太重要了
Don't jump. Let's try it again, puppy.
别跳，再来一遍
Stay still. Stay.
乖乖的
- Stanley! - Hello, baby.
- 斯坦利 - 哈罗，亲爱的
My, the army stuck with you.
天啊，你还真有军人的模样
The army's made me hungry.
我饿了
What do you got in the icebox to eat?
冰箱里有什么吃的？
Boy, it's good to be home.
天啊，回家真好呀
If you had told me you'd quit your job,
如果你早说要辞职
we wouldn't have gotten married. Oh, honey, come on.
我才不会嫁给你呢. 噢，宝贝，别说了
[But dream forever]
[书名：翻越喜马拉雅]
In your arms
Oh, Lisa
[时尚杂志BAZZAR]
Lisa
谢谢观赏